<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Istio on Andreas Strikos</title><link>https://astrikos.github.io/tags/istio/</link><description>Recent content in Istio on Andreas Strikos</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://astrikos.github.io/tags/istio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Demystifying Kubernetes networking using TCPDUMP</title><link>https://astrikos.github.io/2022/06/demystifying-kubernetes-networking-using-tcpdump/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astrikos.github.io/2022/06/demystifying-kubernetes-networking-using-tcpdump/</guid><description>Have you ever wondered how a packet reaches its destination in a Kubernetes environment? How many hops a packet will take before it even “exits” from its Kubernetes node? How do components like kube-proxy and service mesh solutions like Istio and Linkerd influence the flow of this packet? One of the best ways to observe packets is of course TCPDUMP. In this article, we will try to demystify Kubernetes and Istio networking behaviours and see in practice how these tools work by using TCP streams from TCPDUMP.</description></item><item><title>Sometimes It's Not Always DNS</title><link>https://astrikos.github.io/2021/07/sometimes-its-not-always-dns/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://astrikos.github.io/2021/07/sometimes-its-not-always-dns/</guid><description>Beat’s infrastructure architecture consists of multiple islands that each one of them contains a separate Kubernetes cluster. Recently we took the decision to allow services from different clusters to be able to discover each other. Since we were already using Istio we decided to leverage Istio’s multi cluster capability.
After preparing our setup and testing it with some of our home grown tools, we tried to switch one of our lower traffic services to use Istio’s multi cluster discovery.</description></item></channel></rss>